type Question = {
  question: string;
  answers: string[];
  correctAnswer: string;
};


export const H2cellorganellesdata = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: "What is the primary function of ribosomes?",
      answers: ["Lipid synthesis",
       "Protein synthesis",
       "DNA replication",
       "RNA transcription",
       "Carbohydrate metabolism"],
      correctAnswer: "Protein synthesis"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where are the rRNA molecules of ribosomes synthesized?",
      answers: ["Cytoplasm",
       "Mitochondria",
       "Nucleus",
       "Endoplasmic reticulum",
       "Golgi apparatus"],
      correctAnswer: "Nucleus"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the function of polyribosomes?",
      answers: ["Lipid metabolism",
       "Protein folding",
       "Protein synthesis",
       "DNA repair",
       "RNA splicing"],
      correctAnswer: "Protein synthesis"
    },
    {
      question: "What confers basophilic staining properties on ribosomes?",
      answers: ["Proteins",
       "Lipids",
       "Carbohydrates",
       "Phosphate groups",
       "RNA"],
      correctAnswer: "Phosphate groups"
    },
    {
      question: "Which type of ER is prominent in cells specialized for protein secretion?",
      answers: ["Smooth ER",
       "Transitional ER",
       "Rough ER",
       "Golgi ER",
       "Cytosolic ER"],
      correctAnswer: "Rough ER"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the primary function of smooth endoplasmic reticulum?",
      answers: ["Protein synthesis",
       "Lipid metabolism",
       "DNA replication",
       "RNA transcription",
       "Carbohydrate metabolism"],
      correctAnswer: "Lipid metabolism"
    },
    {
      question: "Where are the enzymes for glycosylation located?",
      answers: ["Cytoplasm",
       "Nucleus",
       "Mitochondria",
       "Golgi apparatus",
       "Endoplasmic reticulum"],
      correctAnswer: "Golgi apparatus"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the role of the signal-recognition particle (SRP) in protein synthesis?",
      answers: ["Initiates transcription",
       "Binds to DNA",
       "Inhibits polypeptide elongation",
       "Synthesizes mRNA",
       "Degrades misfolded proteins"],
      correctAnswer: "Inhibits polypeptide elongation"
    },
    {
      question: "What organelle is responsible for the initial glycosylation of glycoproteins?",
      answers: ["Nucleus",
       "Lysosome",
       "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
       "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
       "Mitochondria"],
      correctAnswer: "Rough endoplasmic reticulum"
    },
    {
      question: "Which structure is involved in the degradation of nonfunctional proteins?",
      answers: ["Nucleus",
       "Mitochondria",
       "Proteasomes",
       "Peroxisomes",
       "Lysosomes"],
      correctAnswer: "Proteasomes"
    },
    {
      question: "What molecule targets denatured proteins for breakdown by proteasomes?",
      answers: ["Chaperone",
       "Ubiquitin",
       "tRNA",
       "ATP",
       "rRNA"],
      correctAnswer: "Ubiquitin"
    }
  ] as Question[]
};
    
  //   ,
  //   {
  //     "question": "What is the function of the Golgi apparatus?",
  //     "option1": "DNA replication",
  //     "option2": "Lipid synthesis",
  //     "option3": "Protein modification and packaging",
  //     "option4": "RNA synthesis",
  //     "option5": "ATP production",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What are lysosomes primarily responsible for?",
  //     "option1": "Protein synthesis",
  //     "option2": "Lipid metabolism",
  //     "option3": "Intracellular digestion",
  //     "option4": "DNA replication",
  //     "option5": "RNA transcription",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Which organelle contains enzymes for detoxification reactions?",
  //     "option1": "Nucleus",
  //     "option2": "Mitochondria",
  //     "option3": "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option4": "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option5": "Golgi apparatus",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Which process involves the breakdown of cellular components by lysosomes?",
  //     "option1": "Exocytosis",
  //     "option2": "Endocytosis",
  //     "option3": "Autophagy",
  //     "option4": "Phagocytosis",
  //     "option5": "Pinocytosis",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Where are mitochondrial enzymes for aerobic respiration located?",
  //     "option1": "Outer membrane",
  //     "option2": "Inner membrane",
  //     "option3": "Intermembrane space",
  //     "option4": "Matrix",
  //     "option5": "Cristae",
  //     "ans": 2
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What is the function of the ATP synthase complex in mitochondria?",
  //     "option1": "DNA synthesis",
  //     "option2": "Protein folding",
  //     "option3": "ATP production",
  //     "option4": "Lipid synthesis",
  //     "option5": "RNA transcription",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What type of DNA do mitochondria contain?",
  //     "option1": "Linear",
  //     "option2": "Circular",
  //     "option3": "Fragmented",
  //     "option4": "Double-stranded",
  //     "option5": "Single-stranded",
  //     "ans": 2
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Which organelle is involved in the synthesis of steroid hormones?",
  //     "option1": "Nucleus",
  //     "option2": "Mitochondria",
  //     "option3": "Golgi apparatus",
  //     "option4": "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option5": "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "ans": 5
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What structure is associated with the posttranslational modification of proteins?",
  //     "option1": "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option2": "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option3": "Golgi apparatus",
  //     "option4": "Lysosome",
  //     "option5": "Nucleus",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Which organelle is responsible for the production of ATP through oxidative phosphorylation?",
  //     "option1": "Nucleus",
  //     "option2": "Mitochondria",
  //     "option3": "Golgi apparatus",
  //     "option4": "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option5": "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "ans": 2
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What is the primary function of the endoplasmic reticulum?",
  //     "option1": "Protein synthesis",
  //     "option2": "Lipid metabolism",
  //     "option3": "DNA replication",
  //     "option4": "RNA transcription",
  //     "option5": "Carbohydrate metabolism",
  //     "ans": 1
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What role do chaperones play in the cell?",
  //     "option1": "DNA replication",
  //     "option2": "Protein folding",
  //     "option3": "RNA synthesis",
  //     "option4": "Lipid metabolism",
  //     "option5": "Carbohydrate metabolism",
  //     "ans": 2
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Which organelle is involved in the synthesis of membrane proteins?",
  //     "option1": "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option2": "Golgi apparatus",
  //     "option3": "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option4": "Lysosome",
  //     "option5": "Nucleus",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What is the function of the sarcoplasmic reticulum in muscle cells?",
  //     "option1": "Protein synthesis",
  //     "option2": "Lipid metabolism",
  //     "option3": "Calcium sequestration",
  //     "option4": "DNA replication",
  //     "option5": "RNA transcription",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Which organelle is responsible for detoxifying drugs and harmful substances in the liver?",
  //     "option1": "Nucleus",
  //     "option2": "Mitochondria",
  //     "option3": "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option4": "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option5": "Golgi apparatus",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What is the function of the cytoskeleton?",
  //     "option1": "DNA replication",
  //     "option2": "Protein synthesis",
  //     "option3": "Cellular support and movement",
  //     "option4": "Lipid metabolism",
  //     "option5": "RNA transcription",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "What role does the nucleolus play in the cell?",
  //     "option1": "DNA replication",
  //     "option2": "Ribosome production",
  //     "option3": "Lipid synthesis",
  //     "option4": "Protein degradation",
  //     "option5": "RNA splicing",
  //     "ans": 2
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Where does glycosylation of proteins primarily occur?",
  //     "option1": "Nucleus",
  //     "option2": "Lysosome",
  //     "option3": "Golgi apparatus",
  //     "option4": "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
  //     "option5": "Mitochondria",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   },
  //   {
  //     "question": "Which organelle is involved in autophagy?",
  //     "option1": "Nucleus",
  //     "option2": "Mitochondria",
  //     "option3": "Lysosomes",
  //     "option4": "Peroxisomes",
  //     "option5": "Proteasomes",
  //     "ans": 3
  //   }
  // ]
  